negative verb ending used in informal speech (abbr. of negative verb ending "nu")
Hm.
Hello, my name is Kiina Haruno.
This time I'm here at Ritsumeikan Asia Pacific University in Beppu City, Oita Prefecture!
I've been a regular visitor to APU for quite some time now.
This time we are here to film the Munakata Festival.
Before the festival, when we were discussing the plan...
We came up with the surprising idea of bringing a footbath from Beppu.
It was a student who came up with the idea, so we decided to bring a footbath from Beppu.
I had no idea that we would bring a footbath to the festival.
I can't imagine bringing a footbath there, but I'd like to meet the students and hear what they have to say.
Let's go!
Wait a minute, this tapioca is really interesting, but what is it?
This tapioca is probably this one, right?
What's that?
I was just wondering if it's okay.
Excuse me.
Is this tapioca from Taiwan Week?
This is an international university with many international students.
I heard that this kind of week was appropriate for last year's event.
But this time, it's Taiwan Week.
I'm looking forward to it.
Will we be able to enjoy delicious food?
Let's see!
Okay, I'm off!
I'm going to go to Taiwan.
I'm going to go to the "at" party this time of year.
I'm going to go to the party because everyone I got to know well at that time is waiting for me.
It's been a while.
What's going on? Is the number of people here increased? What? More people are coming?
Hey!
Nice to meet you.
My name is Luna Okuda.
Nice to meet you, Luna.
Actually, I was able to go to the 8th anniversary of Shoujo-tai's live performance.
I was able to see your performance.
Thank you so much for coming.
Thank you very much.
How was it?
It was great.
Very good?
Thank you.
I feel like I made you say that.
I'm here today with the four of you.
I guess we'll talk about the Munakata Festival.
It's been a while since you and Rino-san were here.
Yes, it's been a while.
They came to our live concert.
I'm glad to see you here for the first time since July
But I've seen you in the videos.
I don't feel like it's been too long.
By the way, are you still coming?
The video will be uploaded soon.
After that, I heard that you and the girls actually had a great time with Takumi Saito.
That's sad.
I didn't see that part.
I hope to hear more about that later.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much.Thank you.
Yes, sir.
I felt OK.
Actually, that's the cafeteria.
We haven't had lunch yet.
Would you like to join us?
I'd love to.
The cafeteria?
Go to the cafeteria.
The cafeteria's fancy.
I'd love to go with you again.
Yes, please.
You would?
That'd be great.
I'm pretty hungry.
I'm starving.
There's something on the menu that you don't see at the university.
I've seen Thai cafes.
Diltrien's.
It's a multi-tiered menu.
Thai one beef
so wahan food and lulu lohan.
Yeah, that might be good.
But they might be out.
I know it's popular.
I don't know...
There's something on the menu that I think you should try.
Lulu Lohan.
It's only available for a week.
Crunchy! crunchy
Do you have a lulohan? Yes, please.
I think I'll have the lu lohan then.
The hot charcoal soup is delicious.
Thank you very much. It was delicious. Thank you very much.
Thank you very much.
Have you guys eaten already? I've already had it twice.
It's so good. I'm looking forward to it.
What else is happening besides Taiwan Week?
Next week is Korean Week.
Last week was Lebar Week.
It's fun... every week.
I love it!
I got some wonton soup!
Looks delicious!
Wonton soup.
It's homemade.
Homemade?
Good morning. - Good morning.
May I?
Yes.
Good morning. Good morning.
Good morning.
Thank you very much.
Looks so good.
Smells good.
Good morning. - Good morning. Good morning
Kisses.
Oh, yes.
Yes, thank you. Thank you very much.
Here you go.
Okay, okay.
Rohan.
Lohan. Here.
Is this the kind of food you want to pay for?
Yes, sir.
You have to pay for it.
Here you go.
Bon appétit.
I'm glad.
Thank you.
me
Delicious. I want to eat this almost every day.
I want to eat this almost every day.
And it's made by students.
Oh, really?
Mick's.
The people who were just there went to Taiwan.
To Taiwan.
Wow. I didn't know that.
That's amazing.
Nepal Way and his friends ate Nepalese food.
Yes, it's good. This is momo.Yeah. Here, Momo.
This, oh.
Nepalese dumplings.
Looks delicious. These are made by a student from Nepal at Mons.
Soga is making them, and this, Soge is selling them on the street.
Oh, not there, outside.
Outside.
Outside. -Okay.
That's nice. And I ate that, too.
We ate it.
I eat it every week.
That's nice.
I was walking around earlier, and there were so many students from different countries, I don't know if I saw any Japanese students.
Yes, I did.
Did you see them?
Yes, there were.
I was drawn to them.
Yes, that's for sure.
It is quite common for me to pass by people who speak languages other than Japanese.
Yes, that's true.
Japanese people, native speakers, they teach us.
Well, everyone, try walking a little bit at a time.
This is it.
Do you have anything? Korean.
Korean?
Like "charo moke smidgen.
Charo moke sumida.
Bon appétit.
Itadakimasu.
I think it fits. I think it fits.
It fits.
Charo moquesumida.
Charo moke smidgen.
I see.
I heard something amazing happened.
I also want to hear the story from the movie theater that I told you at the beginning.
I went to the cinema and it was a coincidence, really.
Without knowing?
Without knowing.
I was so surprised.
Why?
He didn't say anything.
Not even you, Mr. Oda?
All the staff, yes, we didn't know until after we went there.
You didn't know until after you went there?
You really didn't know?
Yes, we did.
But we bought one of them a nice monstering.
Just in case.
Like a surprise.
They used all the audio and everything.
Hey, hey, hey.
I heard they're there.
That's why you went to APU for the performance?
Yes, that's right. Yes.
Yes, yes.
I cut it off.
Yes.
After that, in case you want to call on APU, or APU has a view of the film.
It started to show.
Yes.
So.
Yes, yes.
So, you can see the view of the movie, so please come and watch it here,
I told them that I would love to have a co-starring session with them, and they said, "Oh, yes, we would love to see it.
I got the feeling that they would like to see it.
I'd love to see it.
Yeah, yeah.
After that, I wrote a proposal,
And then, I wrote a proposal and thought about it,
Yeah, yeah.
Something about a bluebird,
It's a film festival.
There was a film festival,
Yeah.Yes, it was held in April.
The event was held in April, and at that time, Takumi-san entered the venue again,
So we had a little time to talk to him, and we came up with a proposal ourselves,
We came up with a proposal and submitted it.
We submitted it.
We were able to hold the event in October!
But really?
October, or rather, this past New Year's Monday.
Is it that recent?
New Year's?
After watching the movie
Takumi Saito and APU students had a discussion
After the movie, Takumi Saito and the APU students had a discussion.
Wow, how was it?
No, it was pretty exciting.
I was very happy to see their reactions.
Mr. Saito, you seem to have a lot of passion for Beppu.
I felt that you have a lot of passion for Beppu, didn't you?
Yes, I did.
Simply...
I don't mean that you came to Beppu on your own.
I felt the students' passion for Beppu.
For Beppu and for the future.
For the future.
That's why they came.
I think that's what we felt.
I don't know...
I don't know, but if there's a second project, we'd love to be a part of it.
We would love to be a part of it.
Please look forward to it.Enjoy!
No Saito-san backstory?
Saito-san's backstory
When Mr. Saito and his team first arrived.
Mr. Saito and his staff wanted to do a kind of campus tour.
Mr. Saito and Ms. Lee will take you on a tour of the campus.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I was wandering around with Mr. Lee.
These three were in the middle of a class.
They're all in the same class.
I don't know if they're together.
It was a big classroom.
Behind me, I asked for the classroom number.
And we all went in through the crack in the back.
And then we'd go like this.
I saw my friend's friend over here.
I thought I saw a hat.
I looked, and there was Saito.
He glanced through the window and put his hand on it.
That's amazing.
That's Mr. Bastard, or rather, Manager Immznai.
He's whispering left and right.
And then he says, "woman plus one.
Go ahead.
Correct.
A lot of pictures diameter back of the sales place
And 30 people in Hunan erste
ation
ocham Jim info recently received my first degree
npn npn
el after all so motor
spoon 2:00 kilowatts patty
tilde
n
Meow
I think he's doing it for me.
Would you like some?
I have a lot of questions.
I've been looking at the Batten Shoes' Instagram.
I saw that you've been to Europe.
I thought it was really cool.
Yes, yes, everyone came to see me.
I think it was the week after our 3rd anniversary.
There was an event in Paris called Japan Expo Paris.
So I went to Paris for that.
And I went to Paris.
It was amazing.
I'm so grateful.
You represent Japan, right?
That's right.
I've performed overseas before, but...
But this was the furthest.
Thailand.
It's still in Asia, so there are many places close by.
I've done Korea, Taiwan, and Thailand.
but they were all in Asia.
Europe
There are so many things
The people are different, the scenery is different The people are different, the scenery is different.
The food was totally different.
It was very exciting.
The distance got too far.
France.
I'm going to miss it.
I'm going to try to go closer.
something
It's really fun, isn't it?
You're doing college.
And you're doing schoolwork.
It must be tough.
No, but...
It's hard for everyone.
You know, clubs and stuff.
You've come ashore so much.
I'll do the part.
It's like we're in a choir.
I guess.
On the other hand, I was in college.
I didn't join any clubs or do any extracurricular activities.
I'm not involved in any clubs or anything like that.
Through the university
I'm kind of envious of what you guys are doing.
I'm kind of envious of them, but at the same time
But at the same time
to be a part of it.I'm having so much fun mixing it up.
It's so much fun.
So much fun.
I'm looking forward to another
I feel like I'm living
It's so much fun!
I'm almost an ABU student.
Is that right?
ABU students.
I like this.
I don't know...
I'd like to know about Manakata-san.
When we were talking about Manakata-san's plan...
When we were talking...
Mr. Oda told me
I heard from ABU members
I heard that there was a proposal to bring a footbath.
I think it's a good idea.
I mean...
When we were meeting.
We were talking.
I guess we should...
Hot springs.
It's famous for its hot springs.
I said something about how we could do something about the hot springs.
I was talking about that.
That's what I meant.
So...In.
ABU.
ABHouse is a student dormitory
there is a student dormitory
there
a footbath
once came to the dormitory
Heh...
I remember that.
That reminds me.
I'll go.
Where?
That thing.
I wonder if it's the one that's doing it.
I was like...
I did some research
With the vendor
I got to it.
I like this place.
I was like...
I'm interested.
Here we go.
There's a contractor who's moving his feet.
That kind of thing.
That kind of thing
That's the way it is.
that kind of thing
somethingsomething
Delivering hot water in Beppu
Ooh.
That kind of thing
I'm doing
Vendor
Mm-hm-hm
So...
It came to ABHouse.
How did you...
Oh, no.
I thought it'd be really nice.
Bringing a footbath.
What do you mean?
I'm like...
I was wondering.
I didn't know they'd done that before.
I didn't know that.
It was the first time
I'd never heard of it before.
Move
Footbath
Oh, wow.
That's great.
This is it.
This dress, this is what it looks like.
They put this in the lobby.
Oh, my God. What is this? You can say, "Here's your feet," and they'll go right to their feet.Oh, my God, what's this? You can say, "Come on in," and I'll just say, "Come on in," and you can go right on in.
Oh, you want to go in? Like that.
She's a very nice girl.
My friend and I got in just for kicks.
It's so nice.
I looked it up on various places, and it looks like they do it.
You've been to Tokyo and other places, right?
That's right.
I did it at a place like that.
I see.
In Tokyo or something.
It's so close to the ocean, isn't it?
Oh, it's so nice.
It's like the hot water from your bed is melting all over the country.
That's amazing.
I knew they were showing it.
If there was a footbath in a train station, I'd go in.
I would.
I would want to.
There are footbaths at the station and also at Kijima Kogen Park.
I sometimes go in there.
I sometimes go in there when I'm tired.
After I'm tired, I want to go in there.
The venue is quite a distance from the music venue and the lawn, so I think there are a lot of visitors walking around.
I think there will be a lot of visitors who will be walking around.
It might be a little cold.
I think a footbath would be a great addition to the event.
That's for sure.
I'm looking forward to it.
I'm sure the little ones will come too. I'm sure the little ones will come too.
Hey.
I knew you'd recommend the crew.
Yes, of course.
They're serving snacks, too.
We got a lot of them in there.
Did you get a lot of drinks?
We had a lot of people come in.
We had a lot of people in there.
How many do you draw? I'm not sure.
The one I'm asking you about now is about two screens, and I think the maximum size is about 12 people.
It's definitely a great way to talk to people you don't know.
I've had that one.
If you guys can bring it, please come in.
What?
After the show.
After the show, sure, I'll be there.
I'm sure we'll be there.
You guys are welcome to bring your stuff.
We're also planning a lot of things on Google, and we've asked people to submit their ideas, and we'd love to have the performers participate in that.
So I'd love to have the performers participate in that, or something like that.
Is it correct to say that there was no Hanser-Cross?
There was no Hanser-Cross.
Do we have to have meetings?
It's hard to tell, but we were talking about using one letter together.
There was a big lawn at the venue, so we could make a letter together and take a drone shot of it from above.
We can make something memorable, something that will be a keepsake.
We need a lot of people.
We need a lot of people, so of course we need everyone's participation.
If you can invite your friends and family, I hope you can bring a lot of people!If you have friends and family who would like to come, I hope you will bring a lot of them.
The Guinness Book of World Records is about 1,800 people, so I would be very happy if we could surpass that number.
That's for sure.
There are a lot of people.
Okay.
How many days are there on stage at each location?
There will be 5 days on stage at each location.
And the stage is closed.
I'm going to have to take a break from this for a little bit.
Sure.
We'll take a break from the stage, but please come and see us.
Come and have fun!
Have fun!
The nightly dishes are familiar to you, but they are original kitchen cups made by Ryuji, a cookery researcher!
You can only eat there.
I'll be there once.
It's my favorite part.
The food, the going to school, the footbath
And the footbath.
Thank you very much for today
I'm sorry I have so much left to do, but I've been told that I have classes too.
I'm looking forward to singing with everyone at the Munakata Festival!
I'm looking forward to it!
I'm looking forward to seeing you at the Munakata Festival.
So the Munakata Festival will be held for two days from November 3 to 5!
We will be broadcasting live on Google Channel on November 4 and 5, the 2nd and 3rd days!
Footbaths will also be available on the 4th and 5th.
If you are coming to the venue, please enjoy the footbaths as well!
And lastly, the Hands Across Nakata will be held on the 5th, so please come and join us!And the last mentioned Hands Across Nakata is scheduled to be held on the 5th, so
I'm sure you'll all get that information from somewhere.
I'm sure you'll hear about it somewhere, so please come and join us.
We need a lot of people, so I hope you will come one after another.
By the way, do the other members make the fireworks for the finale?
Yes, we do.
Original fireworks.
That's great!
We're talking about what kind of pictures we're going to make.
Fireworks, too.
You're really just getting started?
From now on.
There are a lot of projects in the works.
That's great.
I'm gonna have to stay until the end.
I'd love to.
I think I can stay.
We're going to have original fireworks, so I hope you'll enjoy it until then.
And on the GoodClickGuigoo channel.
We'll be posting more updates on the Nakata Festival on our GoodClick Guigoo channel, so please look forward to it!
The lawn is open to the public for free, so please feel free to come and visit us!
Bye bye!
Thank you for watching!